<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DIY Easy Projects</title>
    <description>Our informative blog covers topics from diy projects, crafts and hobbies to marketing tips, healthy lifestyle and much more..</description>
    <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner’s Guide to Meal Planning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to eating well, meal planning is one of the easiest things you can do to set yourself up for success. The beauty of it is there are no rules and, you can’t really mess it up. The key is just to start, and to set aside a little bit of time each week to do it. There are so many ways to approach meal planning that, after practicing just once or twice, you’ll begin to find what works for you and your family too.
To help you get started, we’ve broken down some of the basics. We’ve even included two practice exercises to help you map out your next week’s worth of healthy meals!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our eating situations can vary greatly from week to week depending on work schedules, after school activities, evening commitments, travel plans–the list goes on. Here are some things to consider as you assess your eating situation.
How many meals you need to plan for  Take a few moments to think about what you have going on next week week. Taking a quick inventory of everyone’s plans will quickly give you a rough idea of how many meals you’ll need to get through the week, and how much mileage you can get from each recipe.
What you have time for  If you have a crazy busy week coming up, make a mental note to be on the lookout for quick,  slow cooker or make-ahead meals that can served up in a hurry. We’re big fans of the cook once, eat twice (or thrice) approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your food mood&lt;br /&gt;
Things like the weather, a change in seasons, and food cravings can impact what sounds good on any given day. Thinking about these things beforehand will make recipe selection process faster and meal times easier on everyone.
Your grocery budget If you want to eat better for less (and who doesn’t) think seasonal produce and sales. Check out these 6 ways to meal plan for savings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MEAL PLANNING PRACTICE: MAP OUT YOUR WEEKLY EATS
1. Grab a pen and paper. Write the days of the week on the left side of the page and the meals you want to plan across the top.
2. Sketch out your weekly eats. Vague descriptions like quick dinner, leftovers, or packable lunch are fine for now. Don’t forget to plan for leftovers and make note of special dietary restrictions here as well.
3. Tally them up. Note how many meals you’ll need, grouping together similar ones. For example: 2 quick dinners, 3 packable lunches…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the fun part! Once you know how many meals you’ll need, it’s time to find some healthy recipes and fill in your calendar for the week. Here are some tips to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a master recipe list 
Having a list of go-to meals is one of the easiest ways to expedite the meal planning process. Consider trying one or two new recipes and use a few old favorites to fill in the gaps. Every time you find a new meal you love, add it to the rotation!
Find a few new dishes to try Finding delicious, healthy recipes isn’t hard–you just need to know where to look. Health-conscious cookbooks and food magazines are great but the internet can literally provide millions of healthy recipes at your fingertips.
Some of our favorite websites for healthy recipes include:
-	The MyFitnessPal Blog – in addition to being delicious the recipes are super easy to add to your food diary
-	Cooking Light
-	Food Network – Healthy
-	Clean Eating
-	Eating Well
-	Healthy food blogs like Skinnytaste, Eating Bird Food, Kath Eats, Cook Smarts, and Fannetastic Food–just to name a few&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and organize your &lt;a href=&quot;https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/pages/vegetarian-foodand-cooking/&quot;&gt;recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For online recipes:&lt;br /&gt;
-	Add them directly to your MyFitnessPal recipe box, either on the web or within the app. Our new recipe tool will even calculate the nutrition facts for easy logging later.
-	Create a healthy recipe Pinterest board. Check out ours for meal inspiration
-	Check out Paprika, Plan to Eat or ChefTap, or more basic note clipping apps like Evernote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For paper recipes:
-	A simple, three-holed binder with some plastic sleeve inserts are great for organizing recipe cards and meals pulled from magazines
-	Use bright colored tabs to flag favorite cookbook recipes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create your meal calendar Regardless of what format you prefer, the key here is to fill in your calendar with specific meals. Meal planning pro and Cook Smarts founder, Jess Dang, says, “Good meal planning is like putting together a puzzle. Try to avoid selecting different recipes that don’t fit together or else you’ll be buying a lot of different ingredients. Select one, look at the ingredient list and let that help you select recipe #2, and so on.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you use a simple notecard, a printable template or prefer a digital version, it’s a good idea to keep a paper copy of your calendar in plain view. “Making your meal plan visual may hold you more accountable for executing on the cooking. Plus, your family isn’t constantly asking you, “What’s for dinner?” They can just refer to the board, ” adds Jess. If you prefer digital, create a sub-calendar for your meal plan in Google, Outlook or your calendar application of choice and share it with family members or roommates so everyone knows the plan.
Write your grocery list Save yourself some time and write your grocery list while you fill out your calendar–and don’t forget to jot down quantities for each ingredient. Before you head to the store take a quick inventory of what you have on hand and cross off the ingredients you don’t need to purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/vegetarian-food-and-cooking/a-begginers-guide-to-meal-planning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/vegetarian-food-and-cooking/a-begginers-guide-to-meal-planning/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Seek Inspiration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A great inspiration brings with it a wave of power that by itself may propel you over the finish line. Conversely when we’re empty of inspiration, everything may appear hard, boring and dull, and we acquire no joy out of what we’re doing.
Inspiration is so crucial as it keeps the mind positive and centered on the greater picture. We frequently believe we’re in command of our minds and what we think, but even a brief analysis of our thoughts brings out another story: that our damaging thoughts act as a big barrier to our self growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mind is really prone to wavering and doubt, shifting from one way to the other at a moment’s notice. Frequently when you feel a deep inner yearning to achieve something, the mind will initially go along with it, lured by the novelty factor. But, when the going gets fierce and you start to encounter roadblocks in accomplishing your goal, the mind will frequently be the first one to jump ship! By bringing in outer sources of inspiration to your life, you help your mind “see the forest for the trees” and work with you to accomplish your goals.
Occasionally the process of bringing purpose and meaning into your life means you have to boldly step into territory unmapped by most of the individuals around you. You start to explore choices beyond the nine-to-five cycle of eating, working and sleeping, and start to move away towards a deeper sense of being. As many of those around you aren’t as interested as you are in living out your total potential, it’s really simple to feel that you’re ploughing a lone furrow, and this may make you question if indeed you’re doing the right thing . That’s why staying in touch with inspiring individuals and reading inspiring stories is so crucial, as it lets you see that other people have been in same place as you. If they’ve gone on to accomplish their goals, then why can’t you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the mind gets bored of new things really quickly, you perpetually need to refill your source of inspiration:
Having like minded individuals around you can be excellent in that regard - you are able to guarantee that if one individual in the group isn’t feeling particularly inspired, somebody else will be, and their inspiration will act as a lift-me-up tonic. Likewise, together you serve as a valuable source of fresh ideas - when one individual discovers something that works for them, and then he or she may share that with everybody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forever keeping a sense of newness in what you do is always crucial - for instance, to stop my meditation practice from getting dull and uninspired, I frequently add a fresh piece of music to my morning routine, or redecorate my meditation space.
Reading may be a powerful source of inspiration, as it directly bears upon the mind. Reading personal inspiration stories may be particularly powerful, as you are able to put yourself in the shoes of that individual and imagine yourself overcoming those roadblocks.
You are able to utilize the inspiration you have as a launching pad to increase your ambition - your inner yearning for fulfillment. Many individuals who give seminars on success in different areas all state the same thing - that the difference between accomplishing a goal and not accomplishing it is merely whether you desired it badly enough. 
The very act of increasing your ambition helps to inwardly move you away from the situation you’re disgruntled with, and you feel that inside your heart you’re really beginning to bring about the changes that you wish to see in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/seek-inspiration/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/seek-inspiration/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Regarding customers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Companies which have a satisfactory percentage of loyal customers have the advantage of channeling funds into a self reinforcing system in which the company delivers constantly evolving superior value and high quality products and services. 
This will further create the comfortable relationship desired to continue to successfully keep the customers both happy and loyal. 
There is also the added advantage of the preexisting customers who consciously help to introduce friends and family to consider using the products and services based on personal testimonies and enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to discern one’s position with regards to the customer loyalty ratio can be rather tricky if not virtually impossible sometimes. However thankfully there are some tried and true methods that can be used to achieve this goal. Being able to retain a loyal customer base has its merits and understanding the customer sentiment is pivotal to achieving this loyalty factor. 
As loyal customers are a good indicator to a thriving and consistently successful business endeavor, taking the time to focus on understanding the level of each customer’s loyalty is both prudent and beneficial in the long term state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting feedback of the level of satisfaction derived from using the product or the lack of said satisfaction. Armed with this information, there should also be a proactive counter action to address any negative feedback learnt.
Sometimes however such information can be rather difficult to process as the customer themselves may not entirely know what they specifically need or want. This can be looked upon as an advantage on the part of the seller as it creates the opportunity for the seller to promote the product or service in a way that is attractive to the customer.
It is important to get all the information you can about customer service and keeping your customers happy to further your business. Get started today!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/regarding-customers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/regarding-customers/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting in Touch with Oneself using Transcendental Meditation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Each human being is a masterpiece, a source of limitless energy and potential. Within each person, there is a vast well of power, knowledge, and life. Each is created with a mind and a soul that instinctively rises above to meet the infinite boundaries of being.
The quest for happiness, for &lt;a href=&quot;https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/pages/prosperity-pursuit/&quot;&gt;success&lt;/a&gt; , and for a better quality of living is endless among most people. Many look forward to the promises of tomorrow for a more pleasant life. Some, on the other hand, cling to various things for joy and satisfaction. However, do you know that many of the things that most people dream today are actually hidden within them? These are only waiting to be discovered and unleashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transcendental meditation revolves around this purpose – to help a person successfully bridge the gap that separates him from his inner self and to discover the treasures lurking within him in the process. Transcendental meditation can be traced back to the year 1957, originating from India’s Vedic tradition. This specific type of meditation primarily works using a certain utterance called mantra. The idea behind this activity is to reiterate the given mantra following specific principles and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When successfully performed, the result is the attainment of a specific state of mind that is called transcendental consciousness. Once you attain this state, you will experience a sense of tranquility and alertness. These two senses of being may make you think that transcendental consciousness is ironic in nature. However, this can actually be achieved, and the benefits are overwhelming.
Practicing transcendental meditation is a way to calm the body and the mind, to free it from the binds of the material world. You will not need to exert too much effort to achieve this. No concentration is even required. You do not have to do anything. With the mantra as your guide, you will be able to transcend worldly thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once free from the bounds of material perceptions, only then will you be able to discover the pool of potentials that you have. Your intellect will reveal to you truths that have been hidden in the depths of your soul and riches that you may never even know exist in you. By looking inward, you keep in touch with yourself and bring to life all those dormant potentials that have been endowed to you since you were born.
The challenge to every person who practices transcendental meditation is to be able to bring his hidden potential out into his daily life. This activity only requires about twenty minutes of your time, performed two times a day, to be able to take effect in its best form. With practice, you can easily learn the technique and witness the changes that it will bring your life. It is geared towards the growth of the entire self. By drawing energy from within, you will be able to improve your outer self and your whole life. Once the gap has been bridged, you can expect to experience a new personality, a new lifestyle, and a much better outlook in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/getting-in-touch-with-oneself-using-transcendental-meditation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/prosperity-pursuit/getting-in-touch-with-oneself-using-transcendental-meditation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Forex Trading: The Best Hours to Trade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One kind of financial market that made a lot of people earn a lot of money is the Forex market.
Aside from the fact that the Forex market can give you an opportunity to earn a lot of money, you should also know that Forex is the largest and the most liquid financial market in the world with trade exchanges that amounts up to trillions of dollars each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forex also operates 24 hours a day and therefore making it the most liquid market in the world.
However, Forex is also a very risky market. Besides that fact that it generated a lot of people to become rich, it also made a lot of people lose large amounts of money. Therefore, you should consider that you should think twice before entering this financial market. You should have enough knowledge and skills before you enter this market. Part of the knowledge that you should know the best time you should enter this very liquid and very large market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure you know how to trade, you know what currency pairs to trade, and you even know how to read charts. Perhaps, you also know one or two strategy when trading in the Forex market. However, you should also consider the fact that because the Forex market operates 24 hours a day, you need to know when you should trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every minute in the Forex market counts. One minute you notice a currency is increasing in value, the next you notice that the same kind of currency you noticed a minute ago is decreasing in value. This is why you should consider the fact that Forex market is a very dynamic market with lots of price oscillations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minute by minute events are very important in order for you to be successful. Because of this feature that is found in the Forex market, you, as a Forex trader, can enter the market a number of times a day. This will allow you to earn some profits after every number of trades you do and perhaps maybe even lose one if you made the wrong trading decision.
Firstly, you have to remember that the Forex market beings at Sunday at 5PM EST to Friday at 4PM EST then it beings again at 5PM EST. Trading begins in Forex at New Zealand next at Australia followed by Asia, in the Middle East, Europe and ends in America. The major markets in Forex are London, Tokyo and New York with trading activities the heaviest when major markets overlap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basing from the times, you will see that there will always be someone anywhere in the world who is buying and selling currencies. You will see that when one market closes, another market opens. Trading in the Forex market is 24 hours a day.
Forex market transaction volume is always high during the whole day. However, it peaks the highest when the Asian market, the European market and the US market opens at the same time.
These are the trading hours in the Forex market you have to trade in, in order to get the highest possible trades. This are the hours that are also the most profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the open market times that you can use as reference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New York – 8am to 4pm EST&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;London – 2am to 12nn EST&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Great Britain – 3am to 11am EST&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tokyo – 8pm to 4am EST&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Australia – 7pm to 3am EST&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the schedule and study it, you will see that there are two instances where two of the major markets overlap on trading hours. These are between 2am and 4am EST with Asian and European markets and 8am to 12pm EST with European and North American.
These are the things you should remember when trading in the Forex market. It is not only important that you know how to trade and know some strategies on Forex trading, But, you should also know when is the best time to trade in this very large and very liquid market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow all these, you can be sure that you can earn a potentially higher profit than on other trading times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/forex-trading/forex-trading-the-best-hours-to-trade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/forex-trading/forex-trading-the-best-hours-to-trade/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business Opportunities and Quick Tips for Women Entrepreneurs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you one of the women who happened to be yourself, a mom, a wife and a businesswoman altogether? Well, American women seem to have morphed into super ladies who can do any works demanded from them. From house cleaning to child rearing and into developing their own businesses. 
Well, there are just too many opportunities for mom entrepreneurs that you may even find yourself overwhelmed when you see the whole spectrum of chancing on the career of your life. You may not have realized it but you see, you have the potential of not only becoming a housewife to you husband or mom to your kids but also the master of your own business unit.
However, not all of us women can tough the tides and perform all our tasks simultaneously. Somehow, we have to sacrifice a thing or another. But this must not be the case. If there is a way that you may find to balance everything, then you no longer would have problems on sacrificing anything. You just have to divide things equally in the many aspect of the life you are trying to pursue.
Being a mom entrepreneur entails you to find your vein, find where you are really good at and find an activity that you love doing and in return would generate an income for you. This way, you need not get tired of your “work’ but will only enjoy working on your income. 
If you would not want compromising anything from your being you, you can try a business that is home based. Atleast, you can have income while staying at the comforts of your home and while raising your kids. Thinking that this would not allow you focus? Actually, it will. 
Think of this- you can help your husband with the support for your finances while rearing your children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home based opportunities for mom entrepreneurs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pet-Based Products
There is nothing that indulgent pet owners wont do for their pets. If you can tap on the opportunities that this reality presents, you are sure to be on the road to financial freedom. You may try retailing pet products among your friends first to test grounds. Then go about the block and spread the news. There is too little chance that this wont click. The next phase would deliver you to promoting your products online. There, real business happens.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In-Home Beauty Services
Some women just have the talent making people feel good about themselves. You can choose to enterprise on home beauty services. We have this unexplainable contentment when someone knocks to our doors and deliver beauty and youthful look. Well, probably that’s one way of experiencing luxury. Being a mom, you can invest less on this while actually earning good cash.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Catering services
Great for mom entrepreneurs with passion in kitchen stuffs. Catering doesn’t start with big parties alone. Because America has grown too busy to take charge in the kitchen, many families are now finding themselves eating outside for dinner or having their foods brought in from the restaurant. Well, this type of living can be monotonous at times and all we have to do is to create innovations on making dinner a little more exciting while cutting the prices down. If you have the kick for careful planning in preparing and planning nourishment for people, and make appealing foods and deliver them straight to the customers doorsteps then catering services will be a great one for you. Who knows, this might also be a good time for you and your children to spend time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those were only three of the business opportunities any mom may try venturing into. Be careful though, as a mom entrepreneur you also have other commitments that you must keep in mind. Commitments to your husband, to your kids, to you business and to your self. And somehow, there’d be days like you cant actually have sufficient time for anyone of them, not even for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you see this coming, take things slow and give a break for yourself. And keep in mind that there should always be a day off from all these. A time for yourself so you wont have to deal with burning out and loosing touch of your goals later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/entrepreneurs/business-opportunities-and-quick-tips-for-women-entrepreneurs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/entrepreneurs/business-opportunities-and-quick-tips-for-women-entrepreneurs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 Benefits Of Social Media Marketing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Because it appeared quickly, social media has developed a reputation by some for being a passing marketing interest, and therefore, an unprofitable one. The statistics, however, illustrate a different picture. According to Hubspot, 92% of marketers in 2014 claimed that social media marketing was important for their business, with 80% indicating their efforts increased traffic to their websites. And according to Social Media Examiner, 97% of marketers are currently participating in social media—but 85% of participants aren’t sure what social media tools are the best to use.
This demonstrates a huge potential for social media marketing to increase sales, but a lack of understanding on how to achieve those results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a look at just some of the ways social media marketing can improve your business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Increased Brand Recognition. Every opportunity you have to syndicate your content and increase your visibility is valuable. Your social media networks are just new channels for your brand’s voice and content. This is important because it simultaneously makes you easier and more accessible for new customers, and makes you more familiar and recognizable for existing customers. For example, a frequent Twitter user could hear about your company for the first time only after stumbling upon it in a newsfeed. Or, an otherwise apathetic customer might become better acquainted with your brand after seeing your presence on multiple networks.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved brand loyalty. According to a report published by Texas Tech University, brands who engage on social media channels enjoy higher loyalty from their customers. The report concludes “Companies should take advantage of the tools social media gives them when it comes to connecting with their audience. A strategic and open social media plan could prove influential in morphing consumers into being brand loyal.” Another study published by Convince&amp;amp;Convert found that 53% of Americans who follow brands in social are more loyal to those brands.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;More Opportunities to Convert. Every post you make on a social media platform is an opportunity for customers to convert. When you build a following, you’ll simultaneously have access to new customers, recent customers, and old customers, and you’ll be able to interact with all of them. Every blog post, image, video, or comment you share is a chance for someone to react, and every reaction could lead to a site visit, and eventually a conversion. Not every interaction with your brand results in a conversion, but every positive interaction increases the likelihood of an eventual conversion. Even if your click-through rates are low, the sheer number of opportunities you have on social media is significant. And as I pointed out in my article, “The Four Elements of Any Action, And How To Use Them In Your Online Marketing Initiative,” “opportunity” is the first element of any action.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Higher conversion rates. &lt;a href=&quot;https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/pages/social-media-power/&quot;&gt;Social media&lt;/a&gt;  marketing results in higher conversion rates in a few distinct ways. Perhaps the most significant is its humanization element; the fact that brands become more humanized by interacting in social media channels. Social media is a place where brands can act like people do, and this is important because people like doing business with other people; not with companies.
Additionally, studies have shown that social media has a 100% higher lead-to-close rate than outbound marketing, and a higher number of social media followers tends to improve trust and credibility in your brand, representing social proof. As such, simply building your audience in social media can improve conversion rates on your existing traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Higher Brand Authority. Interacting with your customers regularly is a show of good faith for other customers. When people go to compliment or brag about a product or service, they turn to social media. And when they post your brand name, new audience members will want to follow you for updates. The more people that are talking about you on social media, the more valuable and authoritative your brand will seem to new users. Not to mention, if you can interact with major influencers on Twitter or other social networks, your visible authority and reach will skyrocket.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Increased Inbound Traffic. Without social media, your inbound traffic is limited to people already familiar with your brand and individuals searching for keywords you currently rank for. Every social media profile you add is another path leading back to your site, and every piece of content you syndicate on those profiles is another opportunity for a new visitor. The more quality content you syndicate on social media, the more inbound traffic you’ll generate, and more traffic means more leads and more conversions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Decreased Marketing Costs. According to Hubspot, 84% of marketers found as little as six hours of effort per week was enough to generate increased traffic. Six hours is not a significant investment for a channel as large as social media. If you can lend just one hour a day to developing your content and syndication strategy, you could start seeing the results of your efforts. Even paid advertising through Facebook and Twitter is relatively cheap (depending on your goals, of course). Start small and you’ll never have to worry about going over budget—once you get a better feel for what to expect, you can increase your budget and increase your conversions correspondingly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Better Search Engine Rankings. SEO is the best way to capture relevant traffic from search engines, but the requirements for success are always changing. It’s no longer enough to regularly update your blog, ensure optimized title tags and meta descriptions, and distribute links pointing back to your site. Google and other search engines may be calculating their rankings using social media presence as a significant factor, because of the fact that strong brands almost always use social media. As such, being active on social media could act as a “brand signal” to search engines that your brand is legitimate, credible, and trustworthy. That means, if you want to rank for a given set of keywords, having a strong social media presence could be almost mandatory.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Richer Customer Experiences. Social media, at its core, is a communication channel like email or phone calls. Every customer interaction you have on social media is an opportunity to publicly demonstrate your customer service level and enrich your relationship with your customers. For example, if a customer complains about your product on Twitter, you can immediately address the comment, apologize publicly, and take action to make it right. Or, if a customer compliments you, you can thank them and recommend additional products. It’s a personal experience that lets customers know you care about them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Improved Customer Insights. Social media also gives you an opportunity to gain valuable information about what your customers are interested in and how they behave, via social listening. For example, you can monitor user comments to see what people think of your business directly. You can segment your content syndication lists based on topic and see which types of content generate the most interest—and then produce more of that type of content. You can measure conversions based on different promotions posted on various social media channels and eventually find a perfect combination to generate revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/social-media/top-10-benefits-of-social-media-marketing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/social-media/top-10-benefits-of-social-media-marketing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to get to $10k a month with a Bag of Potatoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Your lack of success in 2015 simply cannot be attributed to a lack of opportunity, time or capital. If you aren’t quite getting the results you want, first check for deeply rooted feelings of fear – and then move on to a shift in perception.
There isn’t many circumstances on earth that the elimination of fear and a positive shift in perception won’t cure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;380&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7_cbCFqt9gw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/internet-marketing/10k-a-month/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/internet-marketing/10k-a-month/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let&#39;s Get Optimistic About SEO?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2014, we have developed a report that looks at the ranking factors that Google uses which can help content marketers, webmasters, and SEO specialists to focus on those important criteria when developing content for websites, social media platforms, articles and blogs.
I’ve been keeping a close eye on this space for nearly two decades and in 2011, I summarized all of SEO into the 5 R’s of search marketing that were evergreen and constant. Focus on how content on your site must be (1) Relevant and build your (2) Reputation. It must also be (3) Remarkable, (4) Readable, and of sufficient (5) Reach.
As you go through the ranking factors, see how neatly they all fit within the 5 R’s. The report focuses on user experience, content, social signals, backlinks and technical aspects. It includes information on which ranking factors are important this year, how these have changed and developed from previous years, and the benchmarks for the top 10 search results.
Technical
In terms of the on-page factors not directly linked with a page’s content:
-  These factors are the factors that contribute to the search engine crawlers “reading your website.”
-  The factor “keyword” is diminishing in importance. Google, like people, understands semantics, and they want you to develop content that is interesting to read, not stuffed with repetitive keywords.
-  Pages continue to be highly optimized and have a meta description and H-tags. These are some of the fundamentals to basic SEO. This is where you want to pay attention to the factors that will make your skimmable and scannable.
-  While page documents are increasing, loading time is decreasing.
-  Domains with a high SEO visibility have higher rankings with their URLs. They have built up a reputation in the search engine.
-  Good URLs have the equivalent worth to thousands of keywords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a new section this year, reflecting the emphasis on the user experience as it relates to design and usability as well as on-page optimization. The findings are:
-  More images are being used on websites, but there are fewer videos, relating to Google’s decision to only play video thumbnails in the SERPs.
-  There are fewer websites in the top 30 rankings that include Google AdSense advertisements. Don’t distract your users with ads that don’t improve their experience.
-  Higher ranking pages have better formatted pages with more interactive elements that are easy for both the user and bot to understand. They’re also more effortless for reading, which shows the value of creating text that is skimmable and scannable and chunked for comprehension.
-  The top ranking sites were responsive sites that did not use Flash.
-  User signals are playing a bigger role in relation to content and rankings. This is the most critical signal for relevance that Google has. These signals could include your users’ click-through behavior on SERPs, data collected from users through a browser like Chrome, data collected in aggregate through Google Analytics, aggregated Gmail history, and all the personalized search history they have on that individual visitor, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User Signals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User signals – CTR, time on site, bounce rate – are becoming increasingly important for search engines because these are a way to find out if the user was satisfied with their search experience. The availability of big data is assisting search engines in enhancing the experience provided.
Content
Relevant content is king and has usurped keywords as the most vital factor for rankings. Here’s what the findings say:
-  There is more content; however, it is not just quantity for the sake of volume, but for the sake of helping your prospect’s buy.
-  Content has been simplified so that it is easier to read.
-  Pages with the most relevant content most often rank higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Signals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The correlation between more social signals and higher ranking URLs continues to be of great importance and shows the importance of reach. Other findings include:
-  There is a significant increase in the average number of social signals per URL and in corresponding ranking.
-  Social signals are involved in brand awareness, domain performance, and direct traffic.
-  Further research is still needed in this area to better understand the value of social signals on rankings. It is still believed that there are still other signals that are imperative to showing search engines where there is relevant content.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/internet-marketing/SEO-and-internet-marketing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/internet-marketing/SEO-and-internet-marketing/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guide to Emails Sending After Initial Opt-in</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…when people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a) find your site,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;b) spend enough time on it to stumble onto an opt-in opportunity and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;c) are interested enough to give their email address, you should thank your lucky stars.
And by “thank your lucky stars” I mean follow up with them. Here are a few ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Email #1&lt;/em&gt;:  Your Challenges + Wants
A lot of great marketers suggest this, and I do too. Send an email immediately after opt-in and ask this simple question (or some variation of it):
What are the biggest challenges in your business today?
Create a doc where you save all of the answers you receive. Over time you’ll a have complete profile of the challenges you’re helping your customers solve. That’s the stuff of pro market researchers.
If the question doesn’t apply to your business, consider sending a segmentation email. Just ask which of your products or services the person is most interested in receiving. ONTRAPORT allows you to have a link that, when clicked, adds a tag to their Contact record, so you can deliver more targeted communications in the future.
(For more information on segmenting customers for more relevant communication, check out this article.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Email #2&lt;/em&gt;:  Introduce Your Company
People have so many choices these days. They can perform a five-second Google search and find millions of results for just about anything. So when you get an opt-in to your list, one of the first things you should do is thank them, and then set expectations and reaffirm some basics about your company. Here’s an email from LivePlan that reinforces their value proposition:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice how LivePlan uses social proof — “you’ve joined over a million entrepreneurs” — to reinforce the impact and value of their offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Email #3&lt;/em&gt;: Content Follow-Up
You spend hours on your content, and people who download it have a specific reason for doing it.  If you receive email addresses through a content download, ask them what they thought about it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Email #4&lt;/em&gt;: Educational Drip Campaign
Your prospects have a surprisingly small number of predictable sales objections. Here’s a pro tip for you: collect sales objections and come up with a response for each. Translate those objections and responses into educational emails. These emails anticipate your prospects’ thought process and deliver information to them in the order they need it.
Here are a few common objections that might apply to your business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price:&lt;/strong&gt; why is your price so high/low?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Credibility:&lt;/strong&gt; why should a prospect choose your company?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fit:&lt;/strong&gt; is your solution right for the prospect?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timing:&lt;/strong&gt; should the prospect wait a while before purchasing?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authority:&lt;/strong&gt; prospects need to involve other people in the decision.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/entrepreneurs/email/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://diyeasyprojects.github.io/entrepreneurs/email/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
